Found a
发现
web can be done
可以通过 Web
Open agent web.
Open Agent Web 完成。
GitHub compil
GitHub
compiler excited about OpenAI's codeex
编译器对 OpenAI
agent that was just launched on Friday.
于周五刚刚发布的 codeex 代理感到兴奋。
Uh and I'm thrilled to have Sam Alman
呃，我很高兴萨姆·阿尔曼能
join us. virtually. Welcome Sam to
加入我们。 几乎。 欢迎 Sam 加入
build. Thank you. Thank you for having
建设。 谢谢。 谢谢邀请
me.
。
[Applause]
[掌声]
Hey, you know, one of the things I know
嘿，你知道，我知道
you've thought a lot about uh you know,
你一直在思考的一件事，就是
developers use for software engineering.
开发人员在软件工程中使用的所有这些不同的外形尺寸。
Of course, you did the CLI and now yes,
当然，你完成了 CLI，而且，是的，
you know, last week you did uh the
你知道，上周你完成了
coding agent. You want to talk a little
编码代理。  Sam，你想稍微谈谈
bit Sam as sort of the vision you have
你
for how software engineering evolves and
对软件工程发展方向的愿景，以及
actually how developers will use all
开发者将如何把所有
these various form factors together?
这些不同的形态因素结合起来使用吗？   是的
Yeah. So Sati you and I have been
。 萨蒂，你和我已经
talking about this for a long time. In
讨论这件事很久了。
fact the very first version of Codex I
事实上，Codex 的第一个版本我
think it was all the way back to 2021.
认为可以追溯到 2021 年。这是
One of the very first things we we did
我们
together uh in GitHub and we've been
在 GitHub 上一起做的第一件事，我们一直在
talking about how someday we'd get to
讨论有一天我们如何才能获得
like uh a real agent coding experience.
真正的智能体编码体验。   对
And it's it's kind of wild to me that
我来说，这一切
it's it's finally here. I think this is
终于发生了，感觉有点不可思议。 我认为这是
programming that I've ever seen. But
我见过的编程领域最大的变革之一。 但
this idea that you now have a a real
这种想法是，你现在拥有一个真正的
virtual teammate that you can assign
虚拟队友，你可以给他分配
work to that you can say, "Hey, go off
工作，你可以说：“嘿，
and do some of the stuff you were just
去做一些你刚才正在
doing and increasingly more advanced
做的事情，以及越来越高级的
things." You know, at some point say
事情。” 你知道，在某个时候，你可以说：
like, "I got a big idea. Go off and work
“我有个好主意。花
for a couple of days and do it and that
几天时间把它实现出来，
you can issue many requests in parallel
你可以同时发出很多请求，
that you can be fixing bugs,
比如修复漏洞、
implementing new features, answering
实现新功能、回答
questions about the code." Um, this is
有关代码的问题。” 嗯，这才是
like true software engineering task
真正的软件工程任务
delegation. Uh, and I think it'll only
委派。 嗯，我觉得情况只会越来越
get better from here, but but this is
好，但这确实是
just a tremendously exciting moment. It
一个非常激动人心的时刻。 它
integrates very deeply with GitHub. You
与GitHub深度集成。 你
can give it access to a repo and an
可以授予它对代码库和环境的访问权限，
environment and you can get some pretty
然后就可以完成一些非常
amazing stuff done. Yeah, I know it's
了不起的事情。 是的，我知道
really exciting to see that. And it's
看到那真的很令人兴奋。 而且，让
also sort of great to have developers
开发人员
stay in the flow, work with essentially
保持专注，与
peer programmers, uh, you know, the
同行程序员、
agents as well as other, you know,
代理商以及其他与
people that we collaborate with and just
我们合作的人一起工作，让
have the developer pro process itself
开发人员的专业流程和
and the life cycle get faster. you know
生命周期加快，这也很棒。
obviously you also are working on a lot
显然，你也在制作很多
of models and are very sort of
模型，而且非常
fantastic. In fact, we've had a chance
出色。 事实上，我们已经有机会对
you guys have built. Uh just tell us a
你们建造的许多模型进行模拟交付。 呃，请您简要介绍一下
as far as the model road map itself. The
模型路线图本身的发展方向。
the models are already very smart. They
这些模型已经非常智能了。 他们
will continue to get smarter too. But I
也会变得越来越聪明。 但我
think one of the most exciting things is
认为最令人兴奋的事情之一是，这些
the models will get simpler to use. You
模型将变得更加易于使用。 可供选择的
won't have so many to pick from. It'll
选项不会很多。 它会
just sort of automatically do the right
自动做出正确的
thing. They'll get much more reliable.
反应。 它们会变得更加可靠。
You'll be able to trust them for much
你会更加信任他们
more. There'll be a lot more features
。 未来还将有更多功能，
like multimodality and great tool use
例如多模态、强大的工具使用
and integration. Um, it'll be closer to
和集成。 嗯，应该更接近于“开箱
the it just works. You know, it can I
即用”的状态。 你知道，我
can talk to it. I can do a complicated
可以和它对话。 我可以做一些复杂的、类似
coding agentic thing. Um, I can rely on
智能体的编程工作。 嗯，我可以信赖
it and uh I think people are going to be
它，而且我认为人们会
surprised at how much how fast we're
惊讶于我们
going to make progress in those
在这些
directions. Now yeah I know we're very
方向上取得的进展速度有多快。 我知道我们
excited about your model road map and
对你们的模型路线图非常兴奋。
obviously you know when you look at chat
显然，你们开发的 Chat
GPT it's the most at scale state full
GPT 是目前规模最大的有状态
agentic app today that you guys built um
代理应用，
and of course codeex is another sort of
而 CodeEx 是你们
agent app that you build and this
开发的另一个代理应用。本次
conference is all about unpacking so
大会旨在深入剖析这些模型，
that every developer can in some sense
让每个开发者都能以某种方式
build these new agentic apps you know
构建这些新的代理应用，
that use the model use do their own
使用你们的模型，搭建自己的
model scaffolding go on to even do
模型框架，甚至进行
multi- aent orchestration and so on you
多代理编排等等。Sam，基于你们的经验和领导地位，
know any advice you have as people build
你们对
out these highscale production stateful
构建这些大规模生产级有状态
agentic apps Sam based on obviously what
代理应用有什么建议吗？
I think one of the hardest most
我认为，
difficult things to manage about this is
管理这些应用最困难的事情之一就是
just the the rate of change you know if
变化的速度。
you think about what was possible two
想想
years ago or one year ago or now and uh
两年前、一年前或现在能做到什么，再想想未来一
two years sort of planning for this
两年能做到什么。我们需要规划如何应对
incredible increase in model power and
模型能力的飞速提升，以及
how how people are going to build
人们在不久的将来如何构建
products and software and companies in
产品、软件和公司，
in the kind of near future and really
并真正
leaning into the new tools and the the
利用新工具和
sort of new workflows that are possible.
新的工作流程。
Um again, we haven't seen many
嗯，历史上我们很少见到
technological shifts like this in
像这样的技术变革
history, but every time one has come
，但每一次变革到来时，
like leaning in early and hard has been
早期积极参与并全力以赴都会获得
very rewarded. No, it's Yeah. And that's
丰厚的回报。 不，是的。 这话说得太好了，
absolutely well said because at some
因为在
level one of the things we want to
某种程度上，我们希望
really unpack at this conference is
在本届会议上真正探讨的问题之一就是，
what's that app server that allows you
什么样的应用服务器才能让你能够
to take the latest new sample that comes
获取最新的示例
uh and keep moving at that pace because
并保持这种速度，因为
I think that's the challenge we have uh
我认为这是我们
as developers building these
作为开发人员在构建这些
applications but it's fantastic again.
应用程序时面临的挑战，但这再次令人惊叹。
Go ahead. Yeah, I was just going to say
前进。 是的，我正想说，过去
few months as we were working on codecs
几个月我们内部研发编解码器的过程真是令人惊叹
internally. You know, there are always a
。 你知道，总会有
few people that are the early adopters
一些人是早期采用者，那些
using codecs all day changed their
整天使用编解码器的人迅速改变了他们的
workflow and just the incredible amount
工作流程，而且
they were able to do relative to someone
他们相对于其他人所能完成的工作量也令人难以置信，这
else was was quite interesting. No, it's
非常有趣。 不，
fantastic. Thank you so much, Sam.
太棒了。 非常感谢你，萨姆。
Thanks for the partnership. See you
感谢合作。 我们下次再见！
Foreilotch.
前洛奇。
Fore. Thank you so much, Elon, for being
前。 非常感谢埃隆莅临
here at Build. I know you started off as
Build大会。 我知道你最初是
an intern at Microsoft. you were a
在微软做实习生。 你曾是
Windows developer and of course you're a
Windows 开发人员，当然
big PC gamer still. Uh you want to just
现在也是一位资深的 PC 游戏玩家。 呃，你想
talk about even your early days with uh
聊聊你早期使用
Windows and the kinds of things you
Windows 系统以及你
built? Uh yeah well actually started
开发过的各种东西吗？ 嗯，其实早在
before Windows with DOSS. Um I had one
Windows时代之前，我就用DOSS编程了。 嗯，我有一台
of the early uh IBM PCs with MS DOS and
早期的 IBM PC，装的是 MS DOS 系统，
um I think I had like 128K in the
嗯，我记得一
beginning and then it doubled to 256K
开始内存是 128K，后来翻了一番，达到了 256K，
which felt like a lot. Um so I yeah a
感觉很多了。 嗯，所以，是的，我曾经是一名
pro programmed video games in DOSs and
专业的视频游戏程序员，在 DOS 系统下编写游戏程序，
then um later in in uh Windows uh
后来又在 Windows 系统下编写游戏程序，还
remember Windows 3.1. Yeah. No, it's
记得 Windows 3.1 吗？ 是的。 不，
wonderful. I mean I even at the last
太棒了。 我的意思是，上次
time I chatted with you, you were
我和你聊天的时候，你一直在
talking all about everything the
谈论
intricacies of Active Directory and and
Active Directory 的各种复杂细节，
so it's fantastic uh to have you at our
所以能邀请你来参加我们的
developer conference. Obviously the
开发者大会真是太棒了。 对
exciting thing for us is to be able to
我们来说，最令人兴奋的事情显然是能够
launch Grock uh on Azure. I know uh you
在 Azure 上推出 Grock。 我知道你对
have a deep vision for what AI needs to
人工智能的未来有着深刻的愿景，正是这种愿景
be and that's what got you to get this
促使你打造了这个平台
built. Uh it's a family of models that
。 嗯，它是一系列既是
are both response and reasoning models
响应模型又是推理模型的模型，
and you have a very exciting road map.
你们的路线图非常令人振奋。
You want to just tell us a little bit
您能否简要地跟我们谈谈
you're pushing on both capability and
您对能力和
efficiency. So maybe you can just talk
效率的愿景和追求？ 所以，或许你可以
about a little bit of that. Sure. So
稍微谈谈这方面的内容。 当然。 所以，是的，
yeah with with with Grock especially
特别是对于
with Grock 3.5 that is about to be
即将发布的 Grock 3.5 来说，
released um it's it's trying to reason
它正在尝试
from first principles. So apply kind of
从第一性原理出发进行推理。 所以，把
the uh the tools of physics to uh to
物理学的工具运用到
thinking. Um so um if you're trying to
思考中去。 嗯，所以，如果你想
get to fundamental truths, you you try
探寻基本真理，你就应该尝试把
you boil things down to the the aimatic
事情简化为
elements that are most likely to be
最有可能
correct. Uh and then you reason up from
正确的基本要素。 然后你就可以从
there. And then you can test your
那里开始推理了。 然后你可以
conclusions against those aimatic
用这些目标
elements. And you know in physics if if
要素来检验你的结论。 你知道，在物理学中，如果
you violate conservation of energy or
你违反了能量守恒定律或
momentum then you're you're either going
动量守恒定律，那么你要么会
to get a Nobel Prize or you're you're
获得诺贝尔奖，要么就是
wrong. And and you're all certainly
错了。 你们肯定都
wrong. uh basically so um so so the the
错了。 嗯，基本上，
that's really the focus of of graph 3.5
图 3.5 的重点在于，
is um uh sort of I found the
我找到了
fundamentals of physics um and and
物理学的基本原理，并将
applying physics tools across uh all
物理工具应用于所有推理
lines of reasoning um and to aspire to
思路，力求
truth with uh minimal error like there's
以最小的误差达到真理。当然，总会有
always going to be some mistakes that
一些错误发生，
are made uh but we aim to to uh get to
但我们的目标是在
truth with acknowledged error uh but
承认错误的情况下达到真理，并
minimize that over time and um I think
随着时间的推移尽可能减少错误。我认为
that's actually extremely important for
这对于
uh AI safety. Um so I've thought a lot
人工智能安全来说至关重要。 嗯，我
for a long time about AI safety and my
长期以来一直在思考人工智能安全问题，我的
book conclusion is the the old maxim
书的结论是：
that honesty is the best policy. U it it
诚实是最好的策略，这句古老的格言依然适用。 它真的真的
really really is for for safety. Um but
是为了安全着想。 嗯，但
I do want to emphasize you know we we
我确实想强调一点，你知道，我们过去犯过错误，
have and will make mistakes but we
将来也会犯错误，但我们
aspire to correct them very quickly. Um
力求尽快纠正它们。 嗯，
and we we are very much looking forward
我们非常期待
to feedback from the developer community
收到开发者社区的反馈，
to say like what do you need? Where are
比如你们需要什么？
we wrong? How could we make it better?
我们错在哪里？ 我们怎样才能做得更好？
Um and to to have Grock be something
嗯，我们希望 Grock 能成为
that the developer community community
开发者社区
uh is very excited to use and where they
非常乐意使用的工具，让他们
can feel that their feedback is being uh
感到自己的反馈被
heard and uh you gro is is improving and
听到，并且 Grock 不断改进，
uh serving their need. Yeah, I know it's
满足他们的需求。 是的，我知道
in some sense, you know, cracking the
从某种意义上说，破解
physics of intelligence is perhaps the
智能的物理学原理或许才是
real goal uh for us to be able to use AI
我们真正想要实现的，这样我们才能大规模地使用人工智能。所以，
that you and your team are taking and
你和你的团队采用这种基于第一性原理的方法，
also you're deploying this I mean one of
并且正在部署它，这真的非常棒。我的意思是，
the things about sort of what you do is
你们所做的一方面是无监督的全自动
FSD on one side you're doing robotics of
驾驶，另一方面是机器人技术，当然
course there's Grock so you're deploying
还有Grock。你们正在
Grock across all of your businesses from
从
SpaceX to Tesla uh obviously at X uh I
SpaceX到特斯拉的所有业务中部署Grock。显然，在特斯拉，我甚至想说，
Elon is we're building pretty
埃隆，这次开发者大会的主题之一就是我们正在构建非常
sophisticated AI apps right it's not
复杂的人工智能应用。这
even about any one model it's about
甚至不是关于任何单一模型，而是关于
orchestrating multiple models multiple
协调多个模型和多个
agents uh just anything that you are
智能体。任何你
seeing in the real world application
在现实世界应用
side even inside of your own companies
方面看到的东西，甚至在你们自己的公司内部，
when you think about even a Tesla or a
想想特斯拉或
SpaceX where you put Grock and these
SpaceX，你们在那里部署了Grock和
other uh AI models you're building yeah
你们正在构建的其他人工智能模型。是的，就是这样。
it's it's incredibly important for an AI
人工智能
model to be grounded in reality.
模型必须以现实为基础，这一点至关重要。
Reality, you know, um I was saying which
你知道，现实
is like like physics is the law and
是这样的，物理定律才是真理，
everything else is a recommendation
其他一切都只是建议。
which is I'm not suggesting people break
我并不是建议人们违反
the the the laws made by you know humans
人类制定的法律，
uh you know we should generally obey the
我们通常应该遵守
laws of humans but but I've seen many
人类制定的法律，但我见过很多
people break uh humanmade laws but I
人违反人类制定的法律，但我
have not seen anyone break the laws of
还没见过有人违反
physics. Um so for for for any given AI
物理定律。 嗯，所以对于任何给定的AI来说，将
grounding it against reality um and
其与
reality for example as you mentioned
现实联系起来，例如，正如你提到的，
with with the car it needs to drive
对于汽车来说，它需要
safely and correctly uh the uh humanoid
安全正确地驾驶，而人形
robot optimus needs to you know perform
机器人Optimus需要执行
the task that that that it's being asked
它被要求
to perform. Um the these are the these
执行的任务。 嗯，这些
for uh ensuring that the model is uh
对于确保模型的
truthful and accurate um because it has
真实性和准确性非常有帮助，因为它必须
to adhere to the laws of physics. So, so
遵守物理定律。 所以，
I think that's actually maybe uh some
我认为这一点实际上可能被
somewhat o overlooked or at least not
某种程度上忽视了，或者至少没有被充分
talked about enough is that to really be
讨论过，那就是真正
intelligent, it's it's got to make
智能的事物必须能够做出
predictions that are in line with
符合
reality, in other words, physics. Uh
现实（换句话说，符合物理学）的预测。 嗯，那确实是
that that's it's a really fundamental
一件非常基本的
thing. Um and um and being able to
事情。 嗯，而且能够将
ground that with cars and robots is is
汽车和机器人与现实联系起来
very important. Um we we are seeing
非常重要。 嗯，我们看到
Grock be very helpful in things like
Grock 在客户服务等方面非常乐于助人
customer service. Um and um you know the
。 嗯，你知道，
AI is infinitely patient and friendly
人工智能非常有耐心也很友好，即使
and you can yell at it and it's still
你对它大喊大叫，它仍然会
going to be very nice. Uh so that's
非常友善。 嗯，那
good. Um yeah and so um so I I think in
很好。 嗯，是的，所以，我认为在
terms of improving the quality of
提高
customer service and sort of issue
客户服务质量和问题
resolution um AI is already uh Gro is
解决能力方面，人工智能
already doing quite a good job of that
已经
at SpaceX and Tesla and um and we look
在SpaceX和特斯拉等公司做得相当不错，我们
forward to like offering that to to
期待着将这项技术提供给
other companies. No, that's fantastic.
其他公司。 不，那太棒了。
Really thrilled to get this journey
非常激动能开启这段旅程，
started getting that developer feedback
获得开发者的反馈，
uh and then looking forward to even how
然后期待
they deploy. There is these language
他们如何部署。 这里存在一些语言
models. There's you know I think over
模型。 我认为随着
time we will have this coming together
时间的推移，
of language models with vision with
语言模型、愿景和
action. but to your point being really
行动终将融合在一起。 但正如你所说，它确实
grounded on a real world model. Um, and
建立在现实世界的模型之上。 嗯，
that I think is ultimately the goal
我认为这才是最终目标
here. And so, thank you so much, Elon,
。 所以，非常感谢埃隆
for briefly joining us today. And we're
今天抽出时间短暂地接受我们的采访。 我们
really excited about working with you
非常高兴能与你们合作，并将
and getting this into the developers
这款产品交付给开发者们
hands. Thank Thank you very much. And I
。 非常感谢。 我
can't I can't emphasize enough that
必须强调，
we're looking for feedback from you, the
我们非常希望得到你们——
developer audience. Uh, tell us what
开发者们的反馈。 呃，告诉我们
what what you want and we'll we'll make
你想要什么，我们会帮你
it happen. Thank you.
实现。 谢谢。
Gro
Gro
Thank you so much, Jensen, for joining
非常感谢 Jensen
yet again for our build developer
再次参加我们的构建开发者
conference. you were here a couple of
大会。 几年前您来过这里，当时
years ago and we had a chance at that
我们有机会
time to talk about all the great
聊了聊
innovation you were bringing to our
您为Azure带来的所有伟大创新，
Azure and how customers were going to
以及客户将如何从中
benefit and in fact in the last two
受益。事实上，在过去的
years you've sort of continued to push
两年里，您一直在不断拓展
the real frontier of innovation and uh
创新的前沿。我们曾多次
and you and I have talked a lot about
讨论过，
how this may be again the golden age of
这或许会再次迎来
both silicon hardware systems software
硅硬件系统和软件
systems all coming together and one of
系统融合的黄金时代。
the things that I I've really learned
我从
learn so much from you in sort of saying
您身上学到了很多，其中一点就是，
look at the end of the day our joint
我们最终的共同
goal is to be able to deliver more
目标是
intelligence to the world uh in some
为世界带来更多智能。从
sense you can even say it's tokens per
某种意义上说，这甚至可以说“每美元每瓦的代币价值”，对吧？这
what ultimately is going to help the
最终将帮助
world flourish and so I just wanted to
世界繁荣发展。所以我想听听
be able to maybe get your perspective on
您对这一切的看法，或许可以从
very start of what has been our industry
我们行业的起源——
which is Moors law you really taken this
摩尔定律说起。您真正地将
Moors law and put it back on hyperdrive
摩尔定律推向了新的高度。
and maybe you want to speak to uh in
也许您想和您身后的
fact right behind me is assigned GB 200
GB 200聊聊，
from you and we are now just about
我们现在正准备开始。 将其转化
putting that into massive production and
为大规模生产，
so I just wanted you to talk a little
所以我只是想请你谈谈
just the benefits of Moors law so
摩尔定律是如何代代相传的，以及它带来的好处。很
excited to be here Satia in fact two
高兴来到这里，Satia，事实上，
years ago we had just launched the
两年前我们刚刚在 Azure 上共同推出了
largest AI supercomput in the world
世界上最大的 AI 超级计算机
together on Azure it. And then right now
。 就在
as we speak, we are in full production
我们说话的此刻，我们正在
with Grace Blackwell. We are ramping and
与格蕾丝·布莱克威尔进行全面的拍摄工作。 我们正在加速
scaling and building the largest AI
扩容，并在 Azure 上构建世界上最大的 AI
supercomputer in the world in Azure. And
超级计算机。
so this is just an exciting exciting
所以，
time literally two years later. Well,
两年后的今天，真是令人兴奋的时刻。
during that time, we've we've in
在那段时间里，我们在
innovated across the entire stack. This
整个技术栈上都进行了创新。 这
is the big change in how computing works
是当今计算机工作原理的一次重大变革
now. Instead of just the processor
。 不仅仅是处理器
running static software if you will
运行静态软件，
everything about the stack has changed
整个堆栈都发生了变化，
and so uh our processor has changed our
所以我们的处理器变了，
MV link has changed so that we can scale
MV 链路也变了，这样我们就可以
up to a much larger compute node it's
扩展到更大的计算节点。它采用
liquid cooled the architecture is FP4
液冷，架构是 FP4
tensor core we now have the ability to
张量核心，我们现在能够
Blackwell coherently over a super fast
通过超高速链路将 Grace 和 Blackwell 相干连接起来，这
link very important in the world of KV
在 KV 缓存领域非常重要，
caching as we talk about these large
因为我们讨论的是大型
agentic model and agentic workforces
代理模型和代理工作集群
workloads. And so all of this stuff
工作负载。 因此，所有这些，
combined with our new CUDA algorithms
再加上我们在 Azure 上的
and new model technology in your new AI
新 AI 基础架构中的新 CUDA 算法和新模型技术，
infrastructure on Azure together, all of
所有
that together, 40x speed up over Hopper.
这些加在一起，速度比 Hopper 快 40 倍。
40x speed up over Hopper. That's just an
速度比 Hopper 快 40 倍。
insane speed up in just two years. No,
短短两年内，速度提升简直令人难以置信。 不，
it's just unbelievable. And in fact, you
简直难以置信。 事实上，你
know, that type of compounding of
知道，就是那种
scurves, right? Your innovation, our
坏血病的复合型发病，对吧？ 你们的创新，我们的
innovation coming together ultimately
创新，最终结合起来
driving that frontier forward is just
推动这一领域向前发展，这简直令人
unbelievable. But one of the other
难以置信。 但
things you taught me which I'll always
你教给我的另一件事，我将永远
remember is that speed of light
铭记于心，那就是
execution between even the two
即使在两个组织之间，光速执行也是实现目标的一种
organizations is a way to deliver that
方式。
right which is there is in fact uh you
事实上，
know in our fleet as you can imagine we
正如你所想，在我们的团队中，我们
have all the generations of Nvidia and
拥有所有世代的英伟达产品，而且
the new generations coming in and you
新一代产品也正在加入。你
want to speak speak to a little bit of
想谈谈
what Moors law and speed have to do with
摩尔定律和速度在
each other when it comes to driving
推动
innovation. Yeah, this is this is the
创新方面有何关系吗？ 是的，这就是
insane execution of our two
我们两个
organizations now hyperl if you will. In
组织现在疯狂的执行方式，如果你愿意这么说的话。
fact, when technology is moving 40 times
事实上，当技术每代发展 40 次，
generation and it's 40 times every two
每两年发展 40 次时
years, you really want to upgrade every
，你真的应该每年都进行升级
year. You don't want to wait every four
。 你不想每隔
years, build out a giant fleet. You want
四年就建造一支庞大的舰队。 你想
single year and each year let's say it's
每年少量建设，假设每年的速度
10 times faster than the last year and
比上一年快 10 倍，
as a result you you know cost average if
结果就是，你知道，成本平均化（或者说，
you will or inverse to that performance
性能平均化）
average up your entire fleet and so you
提升整个集群，所以你想
want to you want to innovate and you
创新，你想
computer architectures every year the
每年集成新的数据中心和新的计算机架构。当然，
complexity of course is the work that
复杂性在于，
you and I do is not about building PCs
你我所做的工作不再是制造个人电脑，
anymore it's building these giant and AI
而是建造这些庞大的人工智能
factories. The scale is incredible. The
工厂。 规模真是惊人。 这项
technology is insanely complicated and
技术极其复杂，
for our organizations now to be
对于我们这些组织来说，要想
innovating every single year requires
每年都进行创新，就需要
really tight inte type integration. And
非常紧密的集成。 所以这
so that's the challenge, but the
就是挑战，但
benefits incredible. Yeah. And I think
好处也令人难以置信。 是的。 我认为
that that point about that physics of
关于舰队物理特性这一点很重要，它能够
continuously taking advantage of what
持续利用
comes out each year and that compounding
每年涌现的新成果，并且
of that 40x uh improvement every two
每两年就能实现40倍的改进，而
years let's say and then the fleet
舰队
itself will be there for four years 5
本身可以运行四到
years and the benefits of it go all
五年，其优势将
through that period in fact talking
贯穿整个时期。事实上，谈到这一点，
about that one of the other things you
您还提到了另一点，
mentioned this even in you know when you
甚至在您
talked about the first point which is
谈到第一点——
the software the innovation you're doing
软件创新时，比如您
in CUDA some of the system software work
在CUDA方面所做的创新，以及我们所做的端到端系统软件工作，还有我们经常
talked a lot about even the new app
讨论的应用程序，甚至是我们正在
server for AI that we're doing even
开发的用于人工智能的新应用服务器。即使只是
something like even just you know when I
当我
look at an application and its
查看一个应用程序及其
performance whether it's latency cogs
性能时，无论是延迟、齿轮、
even the smart techniques or prompt
智能技术还是提示
caching plus everything else that
缓存，以及其他所有因素都会
happens just makes a huge difference but
产生巨大的影响。但
you want to talk about the compounding
您想谈谈
effects of software that then add to all
软件的复合效应，它将
of what we're doing together this is
我们共同所做的一切结合起来，这对于
architectures that are stable, that are
稳定、
programmable, have a rich ecosystem. So
可编程且拥有丰富生态系统的计算架构来说，简直令人难以置信。 所以
meanwhile, while we're sitting here
与此同时，当我们
executing from Pascal to Amper to Hopper
从 Pascal 架构过渡到 Amper 架构，
to Blackwell to, you know, next
再到 Hopper 架构、Blackwell 架构，直至下一代架构时
generation, all of our software
，我们所有的软件
architectures are compatible. As a
架构都是兼容的。
result, the rich ecosystem of tools and
因此，由于其庞大的用户群，以及丰富的工具生态系统和
all the developers that are developing
所有
on it, they're anxious to develop on it
在其上进行开发的开发者都渴望进行开发
because the install base is so large.
。
They're anxious to develop on develop on
他们渴望在此基础上继续发展，
it because the ecosystem is so rich and
因为生态系统非常丰富，
all of that enables them to invest
所有这些都使他们能够
deeply into enhancing their models and
深入投资于增强其模型、
their algorithms and runtimes and
算法、运行时和
orchestration layers because it affects
编排层，因为这会影响
and benefits the entire fleet. And so
并惠及整个舰队。 因此，
while we're sitting here executing new
尽管我们每年都在开发新一代
generations of architectures every
架构
single year, we still want architecture
，但我们仍然希望架构能够
compatibility. We want the rich
兼容。 我们希望丰富的
ecosystem to be stable so that software
生态系统保持稳定，以便软件
developers investments and all of the AI
开发人员的投资、所有人工智能
developers investments and all your
开发人员的投资以及所有
infrastructure customers investments get
基础设施客户的投资都能
to be distributed and amvertised across
在整个系统中得到分配和推广
the entire fleet. Yeah. And in fact, you
。 是的。 事实上，你
know, one of the things we're very
知道，我们非常
excited about is given the fleet we now
兴奋的一点是，鉴于我们现在拥有的机队
have, we are able to take advantage of
，我们能够
these software advances across the
在
entire fleet. And I think that's one of
整个机队中利用这些软件进步。 我认为
the things that people don't understand
人们不理解的一点是，
that even the things that were shipped
即使是
from you multiple years ago benefit from
你们几年前交付的产品，也能从
software advances. That's right.
软件进步中受益。 这是正确的。
Continuously.
持续不断地。
Uh Hopper, we've been shipping hoppers
呃，Hopper，我们已经向
to you now for two years. Over the
你发货两年了。 在
course of those two years through new
那两年里，通过新的
algorithms, let's just say Transformer,
算法，我们姑且称之为 Transformer，或者
let's just say Llama 70B. Over the
就叫它 Llama 70B 吧。 在
course of the last two years, we've
过去的两年里，我们
improved the performance 40x black wall
提高了性能，黑墙
to hopper is 40x. Hopper on Hopper has
到料斗的距离是 40 倍。  Hopper on Hopper
been 40x over the last two years. We did
在过去两年里增长了 40 倍。 我们
that through all kinds of things like
通过各种方式实现了这一点，例如
in-flight batching and and uh uh
飞行中批量处理、
speculative decoding and uh all kinds of
推测性解码以及推理引擎
new algorithms that sit underneath the
底层的各种新算法
inference engine. And we're willing and
。 我们愿意，
of course all of the researchers and all
当然所有研究人员和
the the the the developers they want to
开发人员也都愿意
invest in improving the architecture on
投资改进
CUDA because they know the install base
CUDA 的架构，因为他们知道 CUDA 的安装基础
is so large. whatever work that they do
非常庞大。 他们所做的任何工作都
will benefit a lot of the fleet and many
将使整个机队受益，许多
users will be able to benefit from it
用户也将从中受益，
and so you're willing to dedicate your
因此您愿意
entire you know all of your heart and
全身心投入到
soul into optimizing the algorithm and
算法和
the architecture because the install
架构的优化中，因为安装
base is so large that's so well said
基础非常庞大。这话说得太好了，
because in some sense you know the
因为从某种意义上说，即将
latest GB200 coming up means some of the
推出的最新 GB200 意味着一些
folks who are doing the cutting edge new
正在进行前沿
training will go there and at the same
培训的人员将会加入其中，与此同时，
time we're also providing for example an
我们还提供例如
Azure container service some of the sort
Azure 容器服务，以及
GPU fleet so that they can run any agent
GPU 机队的一些软件改进，以便他们可以
on it. So that ability for us to be able
在上面运行任何代理。 因此，我们能够
to flex the fleet for the various
灵活调整机队以应对延迟和性能
different parts of the frontier of
前沿的各个不同部分，这真是
fantastic to have. Yeah. Your your
太棒了。 是的。 你们的
engineers and ours are at this moment
工程师和我们的工程师目前正在
optimizing run times on Ampear. Yeah.
优化 Ampear 的运行时间。 是的。
A10s, A100s. And the the beautiful thing
A10s、A100s。 而最美妙的
is because of because of our natural um
是，因为我们自然而然地
understanding of the importance of uh
理解了在架构的整个生命周期内
preserving enhancing
保持和提升
uh developer productivity and developer
开发人员生产力和开发人员
value for the life of the architecture.
价值的重要性。
We support software. We fine-tune
我们提供软件支持。 我们将终其一生不断改进
software for as long as we shall live.
软件。   没错
And so that's right. What and all of
。 什么，以及所有这一切，都只是“是的”
that is just Yeah. between our two
。 我们两家
companies, we're dedicated to all the
公司都致力于服务所有
developers. Yeah. I know that's
开发者。 是的。 我知道那绝对是
absolutely. And then the last one I
真的。 最后我
wanted to unpack is another thing you
想详细阐述的是，你
talk about sort of GPUs is sort of more
提到的 GPU 的应用范围
broader than just one AI workload. It is
比单一的 AI 工作负载要广泛得多。
had quite frankly for you know the
坦白说，你拥有的这种加速计算视觉能力其实已经
longest time. Uh but I think that also
很久了。 但我认为这对
is a massive benefit to us because that
我们来说也是一个巨大的优势，因为这
also means we can bring many many
意味着我们可以处理很多
different classes of workloads. That
不同类型的工作负载。 这
means customers can use this fleet uh
意味着客户可以使用这批设备，
for of course the cutting edge AI uh but
当然可以用于尖端人工智能，还可以用于
many workloads. But you want to speak a
许多其他工作负载。 但你想稍微谈谈
utilization and the diversity of
利用率和
workloads uh that get all accelerated.
工作负载多样性（所有这些都会加速）会发生什么变化。
One of the benefits of CUDA is that the
CUDA 的优势之一是其
installed base is so large. Another
用户基数非常庞大。
benefit of CUDA is that on the one hand
CUDA 的另一个优点是，一方面
it's an accelerator architecture. On the
它是一种加速器架构。
other hand, it's fairly general purpose
另一方面，它
for some of the heaviest workloads. Our
对于一些最繁重的工作负载来说，用途相当广泛。 我们
two teams are working on accelerating
两个团队正在努力加快
data processing.
数据处理速度。
accelerating data processing by 20x,
数据处理速度提升 20 倍、
50x, transcoding video, image
50 倍，视频转码，图像
processing, models of all kinds,
处理，各种模型，
recommener systems, vector search
推荐系统，向量搜索
engines, all of those different types of
引擎，所有这些不同类型的
algorithms map wonderfully on top of
算法都能完美地映射到
CUDA. And so with our computer
CUDA 之上。 因此，通过计算机
scientists working together, we can
科学家们的共同努力，我们可以
accelerate one workload after another
加速完成一个又一个工作负载
workload, one after another workload.
，一个接一个地完成工作负载。
And so as this tail, if you will, the
因此，随着
long tale of GPUs and all of the
GPU 和所有
frontier models move off to black wells
前沿模型的漫长故事走向黑井
and futures, we leave behind this
和未来，我们留下了这支
compute fleet, which is still orders of
计算舰队，它仍然比
computing that can be used for all these
可用于所有这些
different workloads. And so our job is
不同工作负载的通用计算快几个数量级。 因此，我们的工作是
to make sure that that fleet and that
确保
of your data center are fully
数据中心的所有工作负载都能得到充分
accelerated. the fleet is fully utilized
加速。 船队在其
for the entire life of the fleet. No,
整个使用寿命期间都得到了充分利用。 不，
that's fantastic and so well captures
这太棒了，完美地捕捉到了
that real essence, right? Ultimately,
那种本质，对吧？ 归根结底，
it's not just tokens, but it's all
这不仅仅是代币的问题，而是
workloads per developer watt. Can we
每个开发者瓦特的工作负载的问题。 我们能否
really accelerate them all uh as we
真正加速所有这些发展，随着我们在
hardware and the software boundaries and
硬件和软件领域不断创新，
ultimately show up for our customers.
最终让这些复利效应真正惠及我们的客户？
So, thank you so much, Jensen, for the
所以，詹森，非常感谢你的
partnership. Thanks to everybody at
合作。 感
Nvidia for the amazing work uh that you
谢英伟达的每一位成员，你们的工作非常出色
all are doing. Uh and it's great to see
。 很高兴看到
these two companies that have worked
这两家公司
from the very beginning on many of these
从一开始就致力于开发这些
architectures uh to come to this point
架构，如今终于取得了突破，
emergence of computing that none of us
出现了一种全新的计算方式，这是我们以前任何人都无法
could have ever imagined but is I think
想象的，但我认为它将会产生
going to have a very profound impact. So
非常深远的影响。
thank you again and and Satia, thank you
再次感谢你，萨蒂亚，感谢
for your partnership and leadership and
你的合作和领导，感谢
the the the alignment between our two
我们两个
organizations to build the most advanced
组织携手打造世界上最先进的
infrastructure in the world, the most
基础设施、
advanced AI factories in the world is
世界上最先进的人工智能工厂，这
really a delight and here we are in just
真的令人欣喜。短短
two years time AI has transformed so
两年时间，人工智能就发生了如此
profoundly and it's just so exciting.
深刻的变化，这真是太令人兴奋了。
This is the best of times and the best
这是最好的时代，最好的
of times are yet to come. Thank you so
时代尚未到来。 太感谢了
much.
。
Foreign
外国的
Okay.
好的。
for Microsoft Compiludio.
适用于 Microsoft Compiludio。
local.
本地。
web
网页
alpha gracious.
alpha 优雅。
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
小心！ 外国的！ 外国的！
Buu XD Gro Mad Lama cloud deepse
Buu XD Gro Mad Lama 云深海